democracyforamerica.com 2018-12-30

# Democracy for America : Privacy Policy

At Democracy for America, we are committed to protecting your online privacy and the security of the information that you might provide to us.

Our privacy policy explains the information practices we use at democracyforamerica.com, blogforamerica.com, and dfalink.com related to:

How we use the information you provide.  
Information on children  
Linking to other sites.  
Data Tracking  
Advertising  
Individual Opt-Out Links  
When you contribute money online.  
When you subscribe to updates.  
When you sign up for our mailing list.  
Facebook Messenger.  
How to correct information you provided.  
How to contact us about privacy.

**How we use the information you provide Democracy for America:**

We will potentially use this information to send you news and information about Democracy for America. When you volunteer online we may ask you to give us contact information (such as your name and e-mail address) and geographic information (such as your zip code and state). We may ask you to tell us how you would like to help. We may use this information to send you material and to help match your interests to our activities. By providing us your telephone number, you are consenting to receive calls and texts, including those made with automatic dialing systems or featuring a recorded message. You may update your information by emailing us at [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) . Democracy for America may share information with its successor organizations, if any.

**Information on Children:**

The Democracy for America website does not ask children 13 or under for any information that can be used to identify the child. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children 13 or under. Persons under the age of 18 are not permitted to contribute via the website.

**Linking to other sites:**

Our site links to a limited number of other web sites. Democracy for America is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these web sites.

**Data Tracking**

In order to better serve our visitors, we use cookies and periodically analyze web logs. We may also use third-party services such as Google Analytics and Twitter conversion tracking, in addition to other third-party services. This helps DFA to understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our website. We may also use embedded images in emails sent to you to track open rates for our emails, so that we can tell which mailings are important to you.

**Advertising**

We may place online advertising with third-party vendors, including Google, Facebook, AddThis and Twitter, which will be shown on other sites on the internet. In some cases, those third-party vendors may decide which ads to show you based on your prior visits to the website. At no time will you be personally identified to those third-party vendors, nor will any of the information you share with us be shared with those third-party vendors. If you prefer to opt out of the use of these third-party cookies on the DFA website, you can do so by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) or by following the individual opt-out links in the section below.

**Individual Opt-Out links**

DFA recognizes that your privacy is important to your internet experience. If you wish to individually opt-out of third-party targeted advertising by one or more of our partners, DFA has provided the individual links here. To opt out of Twitter's interest-based advertising, click [here](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads). To opt out of Google Analytics, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Information on adjusting your Facebook settings can be found [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217). To opt out of AddThis targeted advertising, click [here](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out).

**When you contribute money online:**

Federal law requires us to collect and report your name, address, employer, occupation, and the amount of your contribution.  If the contribution is made by credit card, federal law requires us to collect and report your credit card number as well.

Federal law requires us to use our best efforts to collect and report to the Federal Election Commission the name, mailing address, occupation and name of employer of individuals whose contributions exceed $200 in a calendar year. These records are available to the public. However, they cannot be used by other organizations for fundraising. For additional information, visit the FEC web site at [](http://www.fec.gov./)[](http://www.fec.gov./)[http://www.fec.gov.](http://www.fec.gov./) We also make a note of your telephone number and e-mail address, if you choose to provide them, but you are not required to do so. Doing so helps us because then we can use your telephone number and e-mail address to quickly contact you if follow-up on your contribution is necessary under federal election law.

In addition to the requirement to report contributions to the Federal Election Commission, we may, in accordance with Federal election law, exchange our contributor list with successor organizations, and with other like-minded Democratic candidates and organizations. We will not sell or exchange your credit card information to any other third party under any circumstances.

Occasionally, DFA will raise contributions through third party websites that are aligned with DFA's interests and mission.  DFA may pay a fee for the use of such websites.  DFA may share your information with the hosts of those websites.  DFA is not responsible for the activities conducted by such websites.  DFA is not liable to you for your use of or for the security of your information by such websites, and you should consult the privacy policy and terms of service of those websites for further information.

We may use information provided when you contribute online either via our website or a third party website, or contribute by mail or other means to contact you for other purposes or to solicit you for additional contributions.

Democracy for America does use postal mailing lists it acquires from other organizations. If your name appears on one of these lists you may receive non-electronic mailings from us.

**When you subscribe for updates:**

We will use your email address to send you updates. You may remove your name from our mailing lists at anytime by e-mailing us at [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) .

**When you sign up for our mailing lists:**

We collect your e-mail address, state, and zip code.

We use your e-mail address to send you Democracy for America updates. We may use your zip code and state to send you e-mail messages about upcoming campaign events in your area. You may remove your e-mail address from our lists by emailing us at [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) . We do not share our mailing lists with non-political third parties; however, we may share your information with other like-minded Democratic candidates and organizations.

We log IP addresses, or the location of your computer network on the Internet, for systems administrations and troubleshooting purposes. We also may use IP addresses in the aggregate to track which pages people visit in order to improve the quality of the site. We do not use this data to develop profiles of individual visitors to our web site.

**Facebook Messenger:**

Democracy for America uses Facebook messenger to communicate with supporters in a manner consistent with Facebook messenger’s privacy requirements.

**How we protect your information:**

Our web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under our control. Our server is located in a locked, secure environment.

When you contribute online, we use a secure server and SSL to protect your credit card number and other personal information during the transmission. SSL is short for Secure Sockets Layer, a protocol developed by Netscape for secure transmission of private information over the Internet. SSL works by using a private key to encrypt data that are transmitted over the SSL connection. Both Netscape Navigator and Internet Explorer browsers support SSL, and web sites use SSL when users transmit confidential information such as credit card numbers. Web pages that require an SSL connection start with https: instead of http. SSL uses 128 bit encryption within the United States. [Click here to read more about SSL.](http://info.ssl.com/article.aspx?id=10241)

At Democracy for America, we are putting forth every effort to ensure the security and privacy of the information that you share with us online. Remember that steps you take to help protect the privacy of your personal information, such as safeguarding your passwords and logging off the Web site after viewing or submitting personal information, are equally important. If you have broadband access to the Internet it is strongly advised to use a firewall.

**When you sign one of our petitions:**

When you sign one of our petitions, we treat your name, city, state, and any comments as public information. We may, for example, provide compilations of petitions, with your comments, to national leaders, without disclosing email addresses. We may also make comments available to the press and public online, identifying only your first name, the first initial of your last name, your city and state.

**Choice/Unsubscribe:**

We provide you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us easily and promptly. E-mail us at [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) . Our unsubscribe requests are processed weekly. To comply with Federal election law, our contribution records will be continuously maintained in a separate secure database.

**Correcting Your Information:**

If you need to correct the information you have provided to us, please send an email to [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) .

If you need to change your email address, you can unsubscribe from our mailing list and sign up again using your new information.

**Contacting us about privacy:**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this site, or your interaction with this web site, send email to: [website@democracyforamerica.com](mailto:website@democracyforamerica.com) .

You can also reach us via US Mail at:

Privacy  
Democracy for America   
P.O. Box 1717  
Burlington, VT 05402

In an ongoing effort to provide the utmost in security of the information you give to us, Democracy for America reserves the right to revise or update the policy used. Should any of our changes be substantial in nature, we will post them clearly and conspicuously in advance of their effective date. Updates or revisions will not be applied retroactively.
